the question is who are you working for
and this is the thing beloved when self
is allowed to live instead of die what
ends up happening itself become
sanctified self is not supposed to be
sanctified self is supposed to die but
instead we sanctify self so now we make
holy that which is purely evil it's
wholly jealousy it's wholly gossip it's
wholly anger it's wholly pride we're
doing this to save the Church of God
that's what the Pharisees did they had
holy anger towards Jesus we justify our
own actions in our own eyes and still
our young people see right through a
sermon title today is the most dangerous
place in the world today we're going to
be talking about the most dangerous
place in the world I want to invite you
to pray with me Heavenly Father I come
before you lord as a vessel that is
unworthy but a vessel that you have
decided to use anyway and so Lord hide
this vessel and please speak through me
Lord I pray
that your word will be heard and that
your word will pierce our hearts please
Lord do something that only you can do
in Jesus name we pray amen
what I'm about to tell you will come
maybe as a shock but the most dangerous
place in the world is the church the
most dangerous place in the world is the
church jesus said in john chapter 18 and
verse 36 my kingdom is what not of this
world if my kingdom were of this world
then would my servants fight that i
should be delivered to the Jews but now
is not my kingdom Jesus clearly stated
that his kingdom was not of this world
meaning that the world and his kingdom
are diametrically opposed therefore the
greatest the most dangerous place in the
world is the church
the world looks at the church as a
threat because the church is where
powerful things happen in Isaiah chapter
9 verse 6 the Bible says for unto us a
child is born unto us a son is given and
the government shall be upon his
shoulders and his name shall be called
we that with you everyone wonderful
counsellor the mighty God the
everlasting father the Prince of wants
peace God's church we are told the head
of that church is the Prince of Peace
how many of you would like peace in your
life the reason that the church is the
most dangerous place in the world is
because it is that is where people find
peace somebody say Amen even if you
don't mean it right now it is in the
church that people's lives are changed
amen Colossians 1 verse 12 to 14
Colossians 1 verse 12 to 14 the Bible
says giving thanks into the Father which
has made us meet to be partakers of the
inheritance of the Saints and light
verse 13 who has delivered us from the
power of darkness and hath translated us
into the kingdom of his dear son in whom
we have redemption through his blood
even the forgiveness of sins beloved it
is in the church that people's lives are
changed it is in the church that people
are called out of the kingdom of
darkness and brought into the kingdom of
light amen
Ephesians chapter five and verse eight
the Bible says for you were sometimes in
darkness but are now in light in the
Lord walk as children of the light how
many of you praise God for being drawn
out
darkness into his marvelous light this
is why the church is a dangerous place
Ephesians chapter 2 verse 11 and 12
wherefore remember that you being in
time past Gentiles in the flesh who are
called uncircumcision by that which is
called the circumcision in the flesh
made by hands verse 12 that at that time
you were without Christ being aliens
from the Commonwealth of Israel and
strangers from the Covenant of promise
having no hope and without God in the
world it is in the church that we are to
find hope it is in the church that God
calls us to be a part of his covenant
and therefore beloved to the world and
to Satan himself the church is the most
dangerous place on earth because the
church is where Satan loses his subjects
amen Romans chapter 13 and verse 12 the
night is far spent the day is at hand
let us cast off the works of darkness
and let us put on the armor of light the
church is the most dangerous place to
the world and to Satan because it is in
the church that we are given the armor
of light amen
Isaiah 61 and verse 1 we will see here
the very verse pointing to Jesus the
Spirit of the Lord God is upon me
because the Lord has anointed me to
preach good tidings unto the meek he has
sent me to bind up the brokenhearted to
proclaim Liberty to the captives and the
opening of the prison to them that are
bound it is in the church beloved that
people are set free and because of that
the church is the most dangerous place
in the world to Satan it is in the
church that error is exposed and truth
is exalted it is in the church that the
blinders are taken off of people's eyes
and they begin to see clearly
and perhaps the number one reason that
the church is the most dangerous place
on the earth to Satan is because the
church is where the true definition of
love is demonstrated Wow Wow Wow
visitors just know that how do I explain
that response just now the church you're
thinking you're thinking the church is
the place where the true definition of
love is demonstrate that the church is a
place where the true definition of love
should be demonstrated amen
Wow the Amen was different this time you
all sounded just enthused about that yes
Amen
the first version didn't work too well
with with some of you hmm okay but the
reason why the by jesus said if you love
one another you are you are
demonstrating to the world that you are
indeed my disciples he said this is this
is the evidence that this is my church
this is my kingdom the king of peace
rules over his church which is where
love is demonstrated the church is a
dangerous place with love because it is
there where the holy spirit was poured
out upon the day of Pentecost amen and a
church that is filled with the Holy
Spirit is a dangerous place to Satan
amen the Bible tells us the fruit of the
Spirit what is it everyone the fruit of
the Spirit is love what else joy what
else peace what else long-suffering what
else gentleness what else goodness what
else faith what else neatness what else
temperance
man how many of you rejoice that when
you walk into church you experience
those things from your brothers and
sisters
amen amen
the Prince of Peace came to this world
to war against the Prince of this world
we've got two princes world
while Satan the prince of this world
John 13 but he calls himself the Prince
of Peace
and so if the kingdom of God is the most
dangerous place in the world and God
plants it right in the midst of enemy
territory
which means he planted it in the world
then what do you think the prince of
this world would like to do to the most
dangerous place in the world and how
does he seek to destroy it let me say it
this way in order to destroy the most
dangerous place in the world Satan
desires to make the church the most
dangerous place in the world y'all
didn't catch that so because he knows
the church is the most dangerous place
in the world why because there we are we
experience rocks love and what else joy
and meekness and temperance and because
when people see this they behold the
love of God and they behold the people
who say they love God what happens is
when people come into the Church of God
and they see love they leave the kingdom
of darkness to become part of the
kingdom of light amen and so because
Satan understands that the church is the
most dangerous place in the world his
mission is to make the church the most
dangerous place in the world
pastor you just said that I know I need
you to think about that pause for a
second and think about them in not to
1618 jesus said these words I say unto
thee that thou art Peter and upon this
rock I will build my church and the
gates of Hell shall not what
prevail against that meaning the gates
of Hell shall not overcome his church so
God is telling us Jesus telling us right
here listen Satan the prince of this
world is going to seek to overcome the
church therefore we need to understand
how he seeks to do this 2nd
Thessalonians chapter 2 and verse 4 the
Bible tells us very clearly a 2nd
Thessalonians chapter 2 and verse 4
speaking of the man of sin it says who
opposes an exalted himself above all
that is called God or that is worshipped
so that he as God does what sits in the
temple of God doing what showing himself
that He is God so what do we see here
what we see here is that Satan is
actively trying to enter thank you
trying to enter God's church in Matthew
13 Jesus gives a parable it is called
the parable of the wheat and the tares
and the Bible says he put forth a
parable unto them and saying the kingdom
of heaven is like unto a man which sowed
good seed in his field but while men
slept while men what while men what
slept his enemy came and did what so
tares among the wheat and went his way
verse 27 over 26 but when the blade was
sprung up and brought forth fruit then
appeared the tares also hmm how was it
that Satan was able to plant tares in
the field what is the field by the way
it's the church the field is a church
and the Bible says that Satan comes to
plant tares in the church not going to
say this to you guys there is only one
way for Satan to enter into the church
there is all
one way and that way is by invitation
Satan has to be invited into the church
for him to have a presence in the church
say pastor how how can Satan be invited
into the church well what does a parable
say while men what while men slept what
does it mean to sleep to be unaware of
something right when you're asleep you
are unaware of what's going on in first
Thessalonians chapter 5 verse 6 the
Bible says here 1st Thessalonians 5 and
verse 6 therefore let us not want sleep
as do others but let us watch and be so
so you've got two options you can either
watch sleep or watch and be sober now
what should you be watching for say
again tears let me ask you should you be
watching for tears what do you think
what should we be watching for why
should we be sober let me ask you when
you're not sober you're and when you're
drunk you can't think straight
and when you can't think straight what
do you end up doing crazy things things
that are against the will of God so you
should be watching to be sober right so
that you don't do what crazy things that
are outside the will of God so who
should you be concerned about you should
be watching and searching self but what
happens as many of us what do we do we
fall asleep and forget about the
importance of searching your own hearts
and when you sleep that is what gives
Satan access let me say this way I'm
asked a question you're gonna be like oh
where is pastor going here how many of
you realize that our church is actively
the seventh-day Adventist Church is
actively being infiltrated right now
no pastor did not just say that
yes I did yes I did our church Worldwide
Church is actively being infiltrated
infiltrated right now and I know what
you're thinking I knew those Jesuits
were coming Illuminati man I just
watched the documentary let me tell you
Church I'm not talking about Jesuits and
I'm not talking about Illuminati I'm
talking about Satan infiltrating the
human hearts our church is actively
being infiltrated the only way Satan can
have access to the church is if he is
invited in and the question becomes how
is it that Satan is getting invited in
he's being invited in through human
artists the only way Satan can have
access to the church beloved is if we
like is if we go to sleep if we fall
asleep and stop searching you know the
Bible says search me O God not search
her Oh God
not search him Oh God
but search me O God and know my heart
but instead of searching our own hearts
what ends up often happening is this
notice Psalm 64 verse six some 64 verse
6 the Bible says is they search out what
iniquities they accomplished a diligent
search both the inward thought of every
one of them and the heart is deep
meaning wicked in other words God is
talking about a people here who instead
of searching their own hearts are
searching out the iniquities of others
let me see what what what are you doing
how do you come to church today let me
ask something do you realize how many
people have left church because church
has become a dangerous place when you
come to church looking for God and
instead you come to church and get
looked at when you come to church try
because you are struggling all through
the week and you come to church trying
to find that connection with God and you
run into you run into this in the place
where God is supposed to be most great
manifest a house of love a house of
mercy a house of peace a house of
long-suffering and you come to church
and leave
feeling like I'm never going back I want
you to realize beloved that the reason
why young people are leaving the church
y'all are not I hope you listening to me
it's because young people have eyes and
they have ears and they have minds that
process stuff like this is supposed to
be the house of God and yet when I get
when I come to church I get funny looks
when I come to church I get looked down
upon and I'm not just talking about
young people because it happens to all
people people were so I need you to
understand this if you if you can lose
your faith in church you now understand
why church becomes the most dangerous
place on earth a church without the
Spirit of God listen carefully to me a
church without the Spirit of God becomes
the most dangerous place on earth
because when people come expecting to
see God and instead they have a
face-to-face encounter with Satan Jahna
feeling me let me tell you Satan
rejoices in that he rejoices in it
because the character of God is being
blasphemy how does the tear get into how
does the weed get into the church how
did you come into the church through the
doors
I like that Jesus is the door amen
all right so we came in through the
church through Jesus now how did we get
into Jesus come come with me want you to
notice with me a Hebrews chapter 12 I'm
sorry first Corinthians chapter 12 verse
13 first Corinthians chapter 12 and
verse 13 notice what the Bible says here
for by one one
how do you get into the church through
the spirit the only way to get into the
church is through the spirit so Satan
wants to get into the church how does he
get in how's he going to get in through
the spirit what spirit is the question
Ephesians 2 verses 1 and 2 and I want
you to notice this very carefully and
you as he quicken you have he quickened
who were dead in trespasses and sins
verse 2 where in time past ye walked
according to the course of this world
according to the Prince of the power of
the air the wot the spirit that now
worketh in who the children of
disobedience I'm answer your question is
there a fruit spirit is there a fruit of
the flesh what spirit is the fruit of
the flesh rom it's it's a spirit of the
world listen carefully loving Satan gets
access to the church when you exhibit
the spirit of the world what is that
spirit sup help me how would you define
the spirit of the world if the Spirit of
God is love joy peace long-suffering
gentleness goodness faith meekness
temperance then what is the spirit of
the world hatred self Envy anger
discontentment pride when we walk into
the church with that spirit I'm talking
about worldwide when we walk into the
church with that spirit we are basically
giving Satan access to the building
access to the church and access to our
young people
the Bible says if you walk in a spirit
you will not fulfill the lust of the
flesh the Bible says in Ephesians 5
verse 5 that no unclean person will
enter the kingdom of heaven this know
that no whoremonger nor unclean person
you know what an unclean person is what
do you think the Bible means when it
says an unclean person listen carefully
the word actually means demonic demonic
is that ringing a bell when you read
about Jesus healing people do you you
you often read about there was a one
unclean spirit it's talking about
demonic possession so beloved listen
sometimes we look at an unclean spirit
and we go oh that's a person that is
forming from the mouth listen to me
beloved if you have hate in your hearts
you have an unclean spirit which means
you are demonic may I preach the truth
is it okay if you have discontent hey
anger in your heart for another
individual especially in the house of
God it means you are being demonically
possessed may I speak the truth when
people come to church they should be
experiencing the love of God some people
have left church because of that very
absence of the love of God but after God
is trying to call his church to a new
place to a higher place he's saying I
need you to wake up because as you are
sleeping to the true condition of
yourself
Laodicea the enemy is coming in and he's
planting seeds how many remember the
story of David and Saul come I need you
to see this First Samuel chapter 16
verse 14 and 15 First Samuel chapter 6
verse 14 to 15 but the Spirit of the
Lord departed from who and what happened
as a result an evil spirit from the Lord
troubled him now what happens when the
Spirit of the Lord leaves you an evil
spirit there's no ho the spirit of Lord
has left me but you know I'm chillin
right either you've given your life to
the Lord organ or you haven't and and in
the context of claiming to be a
Christian I'm not talking about the
world now I'm talking about claiming to
be a Christian the Spirit of the Lord is
love joy peace long-suffering gentleness
goodness faith meekness temperance if
you don't have this spirit in you then
the Spirit of the Lord has left and what
happens an evil spirit troubles you and
now what us all do look at the next
verse and saw servant sent unto him
behold now an evil spirit from God
troubles him it's not God did not send
an evil spirit
it wasn't talking about demonic angel
that because God's presence has been
removed the angel comes in to fill the
place and what does all begin to do come
on guys what what is song what us all
spend the rest of his he's trying to
kill David he's trying to destroy David
now listen beloved when the Bible says
that when you love one another this is
the evidence of my of my fruiting but
when you hate one another it is evidence
that the Spirit of God is not in you but
other when we walk into a church where
there is back and forth and there is
fighting and there is all these
different things beloved what ends up
happening is you have the saw like
spirit that is like hey I'm better than
you
I know I this i-i-i-i why was Satan kept
out of heaven yes he had the eye problem
I am better and and and so became so
focused on harming his brother was David
his brother you catch what I'm saying
but I've been when we allow the Spirit
of God to enter into our hearts you know
what happens we end up trying to do harm
to the spirit of Saul enters into you
and this is why the church becomes the
most dangerous place on earth because
now instead of love joy peace
longsuffering we have discord look at it
again I share this verse two weeks ago
proverbs chapter 16 proverbs chapter 6
verse 19 proverbs chapter 6 verse 19 the
Bible says a false witness that speaks
lies and he that soweth discord among
brethren is an abomination unto God why
was it that Lucifer was cast out of
heaven because he was sowing discord
Satan wants to make God's church on
earth a place where it is not safe I
don't know the context of this sermon
and I don't even know the whole story
but check this out I don't even know if
I'm saying this right
all I heard is the remnants of that
sermon the sermon was this Judas went
out and killed himself because the
church was not a safe place
instead of being able to go to the other
disciples and consider listen I've done
something he would have rather killed
himself because the spirit of the other
disciples at that time remember was
who's gonna be the greatest who can we
eliminate who can we get rid of Wow now
beloved don't take that as gospel for me
don't don't don't don't please I'm just
trying to make a point and the point is
that sometimes the church becomes a
place that is so unsafe our young people
don't feel like they can come and share
anything because they have seen they
have seen the fruits of the flesh in the
church and they're like and you telling
me to pray you're telling me to love
you're telling me to do this and do that
look at what you look at what you guys
are doing are you serious may I speak
the truth
the church becomes an unsafe place
because now what happens in the church
is that we begin to harbor things like
racism pride gossip discord envy
jealousy hypocrisy listen to me
you've never heard someone say that
searching these more workers give her
someone say that the church doesn't need
more workers guys everybody in the
church is a worker the church is full of
workers everybody in this room right now
is a worker
you shouldn't say Amen the church does
not need more workers every individual
is a worker the question is who are you
working for everybody is a worker you're
either working to build up or tear down
you're either working to advance the
cause or you're working to bring about
this score you're working to bring about
what Satan wants brought about so
everybody is a worker Jesus says clearly
in the last day he says if you're not
gathering with me you are scattering
listen man it takes hard work to be
lukewarm that's hard work man man egg
every day resisting the Spirit every day
that's hard work it's hard work ignoring
the pleadings of the Holy Spirit it's
hard work just like yeah whatever knows
it's hard work it's hard work being cold
and it's hard work being hot everybody
in this place right now is a hard worker
so don't feel bad
initially
the question is who are you working for
and this is the thing beloved when self
is allowed to live instead of dying what
ends up happening itself becomes
sanctified you're in catch that self is
not supposed to be sanctified self is
supposed to die but instead we sanctify
self so now we make holy that which is
purely evil it's wholly jealousy it's
wholly gossip it's wholly anger it's
wholly pride we are doing this to save
the Church of God that's what the
Pharisees did they had holy anger
towards Jesus we justify our own actions
in our own eyes and still our young
people see right through it everybody's
working for the church everybody is
working in the church not for the church
in the church this is where we learn
about that phrase called having a form
of godliness but denying the power
thereof we've been infiltrated the holy
war we are now fighting is not a war to
win souls from the kingdom of darkness
but the war we've taken up with issues
policies and people we don't like in the
church that's our war that's our war
are you understanding that while the
holy spirit is our greatest need because
without the holy spirit beloved remember
the church becomes the most dangerous
place on earth this is why we need the
outpouring of the Holy Spirit because
the Holy Spirit does several things
it features chapter 4 verse 3 notice it
with me
Ephesians chapter 4 verse 3 endeavoring
to keep the unity of the Spirit in the
bond of peace what does the Holy Spirit
do it keeps us unified and it keeps us
how many of you believe we need the Holy
Spirit we've got to be unified we've got
we cannot be unified if we don't have
the spirit now beloved bad news for you
the sphere doesn't just pour out on a
church where you know hey just poured on
us and we've got you know wheat and
tares but everybody gets the blessing of
the Holy Spirit that's not what happens
the spirit must be poured out upon you
individually and if you don't have the
spirit poured out upon you you are not
working for God's church you are working
against things the spirit keeps us from
being infiltrated 1st Peter chapter 1
verse 22 notice it first Peter chapter 1
verse 22 seeing you have purified your
souls in obeying the truth through the
spirit unto unfeigned love of the
Brethren see that you love one another
with a pure heart fervently I like that
verse because it tells us that the
Spirit of God enables us to love one
another
what is unfeigned mean you ever heard of
let me think this way it's fake love
it's fake love none of us would ever say
I don't know how you ask do you do you
love everyone in the church what are we
gonna say oh yes yes I do
but for many of us is fake love I don't
like you but I love you why because God
said I have to O so he's forcing you yes
he's forcing me the only reason I love
you is cuz I'm trying to get into heaven
we faked it we faked it and we become so
self deceived not listen beloved Jesus
died in the church it is the church that
put him to death
people thinking that they were working
on behalf of God the reason we need the
Holy Spirit beloved is because the Holy
Spirit keeps us from all such deceptions
and from there like this I'm coming
around the bend to clothes okay the Holy
Spirit protects us why because the hope
because the church is the most dangerous
place in the world you understand that
Satan is at church every Sabbath he's at
church every Sabbath because he knows
that come Sabbath souls are in the
balance so I've got to be in their
hearts making sure that they are not
receiving the word why are because
they got to make sure that your mind is
elsewhere so that these words are like
seeds that just fall to the wayside
because they're not my words guys these
are God's words but pray the Bible says
they that live godly will suffer what
persecution so God says listen he let us
know listen just in case you think when
you come into the church everything's
gonna be peachy let me give you a
parable call the wheat and the tares let
me let you know that Satan himself will
enter into the church and will seek to
disrupt and and corrupt you but don't
worry because if you have my spirit I
will protect you they that abide under
the shadow of almighty Psalm 91 no
plague will come nigh you man that's a
beautiful verse because God is saying I
will protect you from Satan who will try
to trip you up when I was little
there was a cartoon I used to love
watching it was called are you ready
Roadrunner
and the reason I love Roadrunner is
because Wiley you know his name but
don't get Holi only hard work Wiley
coyote yes he was always out to get the
roadrunner and he would set traps and do
everything he could to bring the
roadrunner down and let me tell you
that's what Satan wants to do to you he
will try to set traps and try to try to
do everything he can whether it is
setting the trap he will do everything
in his power he will speak ill against
you he will lie about you he will spread
inference he will do everything he can
to destroy you but listen to me if the
Holy Spirit is in you be beep-beep-beep
and let me tell you sometimes it might
feel like wily coyote is about to do its
thing and oh this is it and Wiley Carly
thinks yeah I've got it
listen to me if Christ is in you no
weapons say with me everyone no weapon
formed against you shall prosper that is
why we need the Holy Spirit that is why
we need God beloved you might be going
through things in your life right now
where you feel like Wiley coyote has got
you let me tell you when Jesus was on
that cross it might have felt like Wiley
coyote got him when Jesus went into that
grave it might have felt like whoa we
never expected this end Wiley coyote got
him but he didn't he didn't and what I'm
telling you everyone in the sound of my
voice right now don't let Satan use you
number one and number two don't let
Satan scare you
don't let him fill you with his spirit
don't let him do the things he wants to
do to get you in his grip because listen
to me God is able to rescue you God is
able to rescue you from the deepest
places from the darkest places saw was a
persecutor of Christians and God was
able to take that man and change his
life and change his heart God was able
to rescue God can rescue you from your
suspicions God can rescue you from your
hatred for other people
God can rescue you from from your pride
and your your God can rescue you beloved
from all these things if you will only
let him
don't let sick and use you guys we're
too close to the end of time we have one
mission and it is to win souls some of
us act like the greatest thing on earth
is what color is the carpet in the
church for many of us that's the great
controversy beloved that's not the great
controversy who is serving in what
position is not the great controversy
the great controversy is about Satan
versus Jesus and the winning of souls
stop taking these little insignificant
foolish things and making mountains out
of them and driving people away from
church smile you could you could do it
so our young people that Jesus actually
lives in your hearts get rid of the Saul
spirits
and here's what hips would race me part
is that some will just not listen
doesn't matter I'm not listening that's
just the nature of it Jesus said
there'll be wheat there'll be tears
should we go pluck up the tear no no no
no leave them they might actually get
converted into wheat leave them that's
how much God loves the tares
[Music]
Jackie please sing for us